Papers of John Beecher, 1957-1979
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Papers of John Beecher 1957-1979
MS 161
Beecher, John, 1904-1980
Mostly outgoing letters from John Beecher to various editors at Macmillan Publishing Co., between 1965 and 1977, but also includes clippings, book notices, photographs of Beecher, publicity brochures and announcements of poetry readings, and poetry broadsides. There are also news clippings and correspondence about the Morning Star Press, later called the Rampart Press, begun in 1956.
0.4 Linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Biographical Note
American poet, labor and civil rights activist, educator and journalist; John Beecher taught at several universities, worked at various administrative projects during the New Deal, and wrote for newspapers and magazines throughout his career. In 1956, he and his wife, Barbara, founded the Morning Star Press. This private press was moved to Jerome, Arizona in 1958 and renamed Rampart Press. It later moved to Scottsdale, Arizona in 1959 while Beecher taught English at Arizona State University. He resigned there in 1961, continuing his teaching, writing, and lecturing until his death in 1980.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series.
Series I: Papers 1957-1979
Scope and Content Note
Mainly outgoing letters from Beecher to various editors at Macmillan Publishing Co. between 1965 and 1967. Also includes clippings, book notices, photographs of Beecher, publicity brochures and announcements for poetry readings, and poetry broadsides. Letters in 1965, 1967, and 1968 discuss a planned book by Beecher on “realities of Negro life in the South.” News clippings and correspondence relate the activities of Beecher’s private press, Morning Star, then Rampart Press. Also included is a questionnaire completed by the Beechers about their book design and printing experiences.
John Beecher papers are also located in the William R. Perkins Library, Duke University, Durham, North Carolina.
Access Terms
Beecher, John, 1904-1980
Beecher, Barbara
Morning Star Press
Rampart Press
Small presses—Arizona
American poetry—20th century
Small presses—California
Correspondence
Container List
- Series I: Papers 1957-1979
  This series is arranged in chronological order.
  - Correspondence:1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: 1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: 1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: 1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: 1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: 1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: 1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: 1977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous undated items and 1979 Interview, 1957-1980; undated (Box 1, Folder 14)